Contact

jleack@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jleack (LinkedIn) github.com/JonnyBeoulve (Other)

Top Skills

JavaScript

React.js

Management

Certifications

SQL Programming Certification

Cisco Content Networking Specialist Certification

Full Stack JavaScript Certification

CCENT Certification (100-101)

Google Challenge Scholarship: Mobile Web Certification

Jonathan Leack

Software Engineering Manager at PwC

Greater Seattle Area

Summary

I'm a Software Engineer with a Computer Information Systems background and over 7-years of experience collaborating alongside product teams. My core competency is front-end interface development, with a record of delivering user-friendly solutions across markets that include FinTech, AI, healthcare, consulting, and publishing.

I've primarily worked with tech stacks involving TypeScript, JavaScript, React, SCSS, CSS, Node, Python, SQL, and AI models such as ChatGPT.

Portfolio: www.JonathanLeack.com

GitHub: www.GitHub.com/JonnyBeoulve

Experience

PwC

Software Engineering Manager October 2022 - Present (2 years 11 months)

Greater Seattle Area

Currently working in PwC Advisory's Commercial Technology & Innovation to develop generative Al-driven software. Over the past 3-years, I have led architecture and implementation of full-stack features for React, Typescript, Node, Python, PostgreSQL, and Docker-based applications that are utilized by a variety of Fortune 500 companies.

My responsibilities include working with a team of data scientists to deliver web functionalities involving LLMs, improving performance and security of codebases, collaborating with product managers to define release scopes, mentoring senior and associate developers, as well as recruiting talent across U.S. offices and acceleration centers. Additionally, I have attended events such as Microsoft Build and multiple hackathons to conduct research on Al market trends.

MBO Partners Senior Software Engineer March 2019 - October 2022 (3 years 8 months)

Greater Seattle Area

As a member of the award-winning Digital Crime Fighters team, in this role I was tasked with constructing pixel-perfect interfaces using React, SCSS, Apollo GraphQL, and Jest to achieve Financial Crimes Unit objectives. Fully typed reusable components such as custom visualizations were built in TypeScript and consumed by multiple projects. I additionally wrote and maintained backend endpoints based in Node and GraphQL, with the data layer relying on a multi-model document and graph database.

Accomplishments include deploying more than 20 production releases, notable refactors for optimization of performance and cost, as well as delivery of critical features that generated over \$300 million in revenue.

MovementX Lead Full Stack Developer August 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 2 months) Greater Seattle Area

I worked directly with a team of physical therapy doctors to define roadmaps and provide solutions for their custom HIPAA compliant health platform. The technology stack was composed of JavaScript, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, and SCSS in an AWS environment.

Examples of implementations I worked on include Stripe payment handling, Google Sheets API read/write, e-mail automation, onboarding overhauls for providers and patients, and construction of a functional prototype for a Gatsby, React, and GraphQL based blog.

Stackend Solutions Lead Front End Developer August 2018 - March 2019 (8 months)

Greater Seattle Area

Tasked with leading front end architecture and development for a variety of web applications, I spent the majority of my time working in an environment that utilized React, Redux, Redux Thunk, JavaScript, Styled Components (SCSS on older projects), and Docker Compose, occasionally jumping over to React Native for mobile development. Back ends were constructed as REST APIs based in Flask/Python and MongoDB.

In this leadership role, I additionally spearheaded the definition and assignment of front end tasks, recommended technologies, led team meetings, maintained GitLab repositories, and managed a Trello board.

Cobia Systems Inc Front End Developer March 2018 - August 2018 (6 months) Newcastle, Washington, United States

Engaged in a short-term project to deliver a refactored digital marketing web app, replacing their existing platform with a more performant and user-friendly solution. The platform utilized big data to perform anthropological analysis, displaying real-time geolocational trends in an intuitive manner. I primarily used React, Redux, JavaScript, and SCSS, in addition to interacting with a PHP-based REST API and MySQL database.

Literally Media
Digital Content Strategist
September 2017 - May 2018 (9 months)

Greater Seattle Area

I worked with the editorial and web development teams to establish a gaming vertical in the company's portfolio along with long-form feature content. The development team relied on me for UX, QA, and SEO-oriented objectives. During evenings I hosted a partnered Twitch channel that averaged around 2,200 concurrent viewers.

Evolve Media, LLC
Executive Editor
March 2013 - August 2017 (4 years 6 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

I was responsible for the direction and growth of two gaming websites. Utilizing Google Analytics to devise strategies in the face of industry challenges, debugging technical issues alongside a web development team, using JIRA for project management, editing feature content, spearheading SEO efforts, establishing relationships with PR, and leading staff were critical elements of my position. Over the years I attended several notable events where I interviewed hundreds of industry leaders and led coverage, including BlizzCon, E3, Dota 2's The International, San Diego Comic-Con, and the Warcraft film's red carpet debut. Later, I oversaw a major website relaunch that included a migration from a proprietary CMS to WordPress.

Adrylan Communications, Inc. Associate Database Administrator August 2012 - March 2013 (8 months)

Greater San Diego Area

This software company brought me onboard to work with its database administrator to manage student, faculty, and test records in a MySQL database for multiple K-12 districts in Southern California. In an agile environment I tested our proprietary software alongside our team of programmers and was called upon for internal IT support.

Pearson North America
Technical Editor
June 2012 - August 2012 (3 months)
Greater San Diego Area

I was Technical Editor for a hardware book published in 2012. This book was sold at Barnes & Noble and made available through an online bookstore.

Conduit Networks Inc.
Server Administrator
December 2009 - April 2012 (2 years 5 months)
Greater San Diego Area

For more than two years I provided technical support for 15 clients in Riverside County, primarily focused on local health clinics that operated in Windows environments backed by Windows Server on HP Proliant hardware. Initially, I was tasked with answering technical support calls and managing a ticket system, occasionally visiting clients on-site for diagnosis and repair. Later, I designed and implemented a full system maintenance plan for 7 clients that brought in recurring revenue. I also performed work on several high budget contract jobs including the modeling of a school district camera system in Redlands and network-wide hardware upgrades for several of our clients.

Education

California State University-San Marcos

Bachelor's of Science (B.S.) in Computer Information Systems, Computer Science · (2016)

Mt. San Jacinto College

Associate of Science (A.S.) in Computer Information Systems (2013)